sustainablebrands.com 2019-06-18

# Privacy Policy - Sustainable Brands

**Sustainable Life Media (SLM) is committed to protecting the privacy of visitors to its website (the Site).**

The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to inform you what kinds of information we may gather about you when you visit the Site, how we may use that information, whether we disclose it and the choices you have regarding our use of, and your ability to manage and edit, the information. This Privacy Policy applies to the Site and has been updated on May 25, 2018 to reflect GDPR compliance standards.

## Information Collection

We collect personal information when you wish to use certain features of the Site. We use this data to:

  * Provide access to content on our news, events and other content and programs we produce.
  * Analyze profile and behavioral data to improve the products we offer you.
  * We will store this information to keep you informed about relevant products and services that may be of interest to you.
  * In certain cases, we are contractually obligated to share your data with a third-party sponsor or advertiser (e.g. webinars, sponsored content, etc.). In these cases we will make it clear your data is being shared. You will have the option not to have that data shared by not taking part in that particular program.

We will not use or share the information provided to us online in ways unrelated to the ones described above.

## Disclosure

Some information, such as IP and your email address, may be shared with the following third parties who help us run our website and email programs. They will only use this information to serve our needs and are prohibited from using it in any other instance. They are: [Pardot/Salesforce.com](https://salesforce.com/) (email acquisition and email delivery), [Google](https://google.com/) (ad serving and website tracking), [Aventri](https://www.aventri.com/) (event registration), [GoToMeeting](https://gotomeeting.com/) (webinar provider). When you visit or interact with the Site, third-parties (including those listed as well as others) may place cookies on their browsers for targeted advertising purposes.

Consenting to allow us to process and store your data is optional. However, not providing consent will prevent us from delivering the news, events and other experiences to you as mentioned above.

## Information We Collect

Across our websites and events, you will have the opportunity to sign up for newsletters, register for webinars, download content, purchase event passes, and more.

The information we gather includes (but is not limited to):

  * Email address
  * Name
  * Company
  * Job title and role/seniority
  * Location
  * Company type
  * Billing/mailing address

Credit card information is only gathered and shared with our payment processors to complete transactions.

The information you provide us will be used to create and/or append your profile. We do this in the interest of serving you with information most appropriate to you. All of the data we collect is kept private and is for our business purposes only.

## To Opt-Out of Targeted Advertising

Targeting allows us to provide you with better and more relevant offers on our site. If you'd prefer to opt-out (or would like more information), please visit [AboutAds.info](https://aboutads.info/) or [NetworkAdvertising.org/choices](https://networkadvertising.org/choices).

## To Have Your Data Removed

If you would like to unsubscribe from SLM communications at any time, you may do so in the footer of any of our emails. You also may cancel your subscription by clicking on the unsubscribe link in emails that you receive from SLM or by replying to such email and placing the word unsubscribe in the subject line.

By continuing to interact with SLM emails and programs, you provide us with permission to manage and use your data as described above.

## Keeping Your Data Secure

We have put in place electronic, physical and managerial procedures to safeguard unauthorized use of your data, and keep the information we collect secure, clean, and accurate for appropriate use.

## Privacy Policy Changes

If our Privacy Policy for the Site changes, we will post the revised Privacy Policy here so that you will always know what information we gather, how we might use that information, and whether we will disclose it to anyone.

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, please [contact us](mailto:connect@sustainablebrands.com).
